♪ Here we are going far ♪
♪ to save all that we love ♪
♪ If we give all we've got ♪
♪ we will make it through ♪
♪ Here we are like a star ♪
♪ shining bright on your world today ♪
♪ Make evil go away ♪
♪ Code Lyoko we'll withstand it all ♪
♪ Code Lyoko be there when you call ♪
♪ Code Lyoko we will stand real tall ♪
♪ Code Lyoko stronger after all ♪
Ants are social insects
like termites or like bees.
A single individual is incapable
of any personal initiative.
All of the decisions are made by the colony.
Ants receive a few simple orders such as
search for food, mark the
path leading to the food,
and follow a marked path.
As a result, we might have the impression
that each ant is rather clever
when in fact, this has more to do
with a collective intelligence.
You mean that an army of Sissis
could be intelligent?
I don’t believe it!
Very funny. Shut up, bird brain!
Settle down, please.
As I was saying,
thanks to their numbers,
they manage to accomplish
some fairly difficult tasks
such as finding food
or defending themselves against an attacker.
It would seems that ants
even wage full-scale wars
between different colonies.
What about killer ants?
Do they exist?
Well, yes.
Maybe in movies, Ulrich.
(LAUGHTER)
But there are, in fact, army ants
that destroy everything in their path.
And it’s true that you’d
best stay out of their way.
And, uh, do any of those
filthy bugs live around here?
No, fortunately.
The live in South America.
Down there, the phenomenon
is called marabounta.
Phew!
I’m glad I live in a country
where there’s no danger.
(SCHOOL BELL RINGS)
(STUDENTS CHATTER)
Saturday’s my favorite day.
No school in the afternoon.
I like Sundays better.
No school at all.
You seem worried, Jeremie.
What’s on your mind?
Franz Hopper’s notes, Aelita.
Last night, I decoded
a really interesting part
on a multi-agent system.
It’s a computer application that
follows the principle of an ant hill.
What happens is--
Oh, no.
Misses Hertz has already bored us
to tears with all that ant stuff.
Don’t you start now!
(LAUGHS)
Seriously.
This time I might’ve found
a way to weaken XANA.
Let’s meet up at the factory after lunch.
I’ll explain everything.
Well, normally I’d love to,
but I have to finish my Italian homework.
See ya.
Uh, no--I have to practice
for a skateboard competition.
Yumi?
Sorry, I’ve got swimming after school.
Buh-bye.
What about you, Ulrich?
Are you doing anything later on?
Yeah. I’ve got to be somewhere.
Oh, yeah? Where?
The swimming pool.
Right. Well, since everyone else
has better things to do…
I’ll just deal with it myself.
Okay. Here we go.
What do you know.
Isn’t that Ulrich Stern about to dive?
Hm?
(SQUEALS)
Aah!
Ulrich!
Out of the way!
Let me through!
Huh?
Is he okay?
Is he breathing?
Is he hurt?
I’ll call somebody!
He looks like he’s--
He needs mouth to mouth!
Get out of the way!
Is he breathing?
I don’t know.
Let me through!
I’ve got a first aid certificate!
(CLEARS THROAT)
Hm.
There you go.
Good thing I was here, huh?
(COUGHS)
Are you okay?
Now for the moment of truth.
Everything seems to be working.
Transfer prototype.
Scanner.
Virtualization.
Come on.
Yes!
Franz Hopper, you’re a genius!
And so am I!
XANA and his monsters
better watch out now!
What’s the matter?
Nothing.
(CELL PHONE RINGS)
Jeremie?
I have something amazing
to show you guys!
Can you meet me at the factory?
Okay. Soon as possible.
(YAPS)
Great.
And don’t forget to
go and pick up Aelita.
Okay.
Jeremie’s called a meeting at the factory.
You coming?
I’m not in the mood.
I’d rather be by myself.
Come on!
If you don’t come, he’ll get mad.
Leave me alone.
Okay.
Suit yourself.
Both of you can stay here.
Both of us?
Yeah.
You and your bad mood.
Ah, there you are.
But where’s Ulrich?
He’s sulking.
I don’t know what his problem is.
What’s this program?
It’s marabounta.
My own creation.
And what does it do, exactly?
It’s a multi-agent system
that functions according to
the same principle as an ant hill.
But instead of ants,
we have these little spheres
whose mission is to search
and destroy XANA’s monsters.
I get it.
While the monsters are
getting wiped out by your ants,
XANA leaves us alone on Lyoko, is that it?
You guessed it!
Hey, that’s great!
But what if there’s a real bug in the program?
Impossible.
Remember, Franz Hopper was a genius.
Yeah, that’s right.
What do you say we go
to Lyoko to check it out?
If this thing really works,
nothing can happen to us!
You read my mind, Odd.
Go to the scanner room.
I’ll transfer you.
If there’s the slightest problem, I’ll pull the plug.
Promise.
Transfer Aelita.
Transfer Odd.
Scanner Odd.
Scanner Aelita.
Virtualization.
You guys are south of the marabounta.
Take the path to your right.
Sorry, but you’ll have to
go without vehicles.
I don’t have enough machine
resources to bring them up.
And watch out for the bad guys.
XANA may have his
hands full, but you never know.
Roger, general.
A krab at two o’clock!
Follow it.
It’s headed in the right direction.
Have you been crazy
about Ulrich for a long time?
about Yumi for a long time?
Forever.
(SCOFFS) You’ve only been
here for a few months.
Don’t you believe in
Destiny with a capital “D?”
Two people who have never met,
but who are made for each other?
No. I’m not really into fairy tales
or cheap magazine-style romance stories.
I’ve had a crush on Ulrich
since elementary school.
I want to go out with him.
That’s all there is to it.
If it weren’t for that stuck-up Yumi, I’d…
If it wasn’t for that big-shot Ulrich, I’d…
(BOTH CHUCKLE)
Shall we go? I’m getting cold.
Target dead ahead.
Jeremie, I’ve got it!
I can see the marabounta.
Well, what’s it like?
Pretty…scary.
(SCREECHING)
I never thought I’d ever say it, but…
I really feel sorry for XANA.
I’ll uplink you a visual, Jeremie.
It’s working even better
than I thought it would.
If you want my opinion, Einstein,
you’ve invented yourself
a nasty piece of work.
(CHUCKLES LIGHTLY)
Jeremie, I’ve seen enough.
I want to come in.
Yeah. Okay, Aelita.
I’ll bring you back.
Head southwest.
There’s a tower nearby.
Got it.
Odd! Look!
Odd, Aelita,
what’s going on?
Answer me!
Laser arrow!
Odd, say something!
You marabounta seems
to have it in for us!
This is no time for jokes.
I programmed it to attack
XANA’s monsters only!
Well, could you program
some eyeglasses for it, then!
This can’t be right.
Did you do something special?
No, except for firing a few laser arrows.
That wasn’t the smartest thing to do.
Jeremie, Odd didn’t have a choice.
The marabounta was coming after me.
How can that be!
Unless…
Oh, Jeremie, you idiot.
It’s my fault.
It’s the virus implanted in Aelita.
The marabounta thinks
she’s one of XANA’s monsters.
Great. Nice work, frankenstein.
I thought we had nothing to worry about!
I was wrong.
Okay, head for the tower.
I’ll kill the program.
Oh, no.
Oh, no!
Whenever you’re ready, Jeremie!
I can’t deactivate the program!
It seems that the marabounta doesn’t want to die.
The marabounta’s become autonomous.
It’ll submerge everything
and everyone in its path.
I’ll brief Yumi and Ulrich.
Come on, Ulrich. What are you doing?
Will you pick up!
(CELL PHONE RINGS)
Wow, that guy can really pick
the right day to sit and sulk.
(CELL PHONE RINGS)
Jeremie?
Huh?
What are you talking about?
What do you mean, the chattanooga?
Marabounta.
I can’t explain now.
Just get here ASAP.
Odd and Aelita are in big trouble.
Ulrich’s at school, but I can’t reach him.
I don’t know what’s going on with him.
I do.
I’ll get him and we’ll be right over.
Hey, Jeremie,
I think we lost your monster,
but now we’re kinda lost ourselves.
I, um…
Sorry, guys.
Take off in the direction due west.
The marabounta hasn’t hit that sector yet.
In the meantime, I’ll find a way to stop it.
Don’t blow it, okay?
I don’t want to end up as chewing gum!
(SIGHS)
I was sure I’d find you here.
What I need is for everybody to leave me alone.
Especially you.
Hey, if you want to make a
fool of yourself in front of everyone,
don’t blame me.
No one asked you to spy on me at the pool.
Spy on you? You’ve got to be kidding.
I just happened to be there, okay?
Yeah, right.
What an incredible coincidence.
Anyway, do you mind
shelving your ego for a minute?
Odd and Aelita need us on Lyoko.
Jeremie, bad news.
The marabounta got here first.
The tower’s unreachable.
This won’t take me long.
I’ll find a way to stop it. I promise.
And Ulrich and Yumi are on the way.
At least…I hope they are.
(ERROR TONE)
No, it can’t be!
Hopper, help me out a little!
If this goes on any longer,
all of Lyoko will be destroyed.
Careful!
XANA’s sending a monster!
That’s crazy!
That krab just sacrificed itself for you!
I don't get it.
That’s weird.
I-I think I understand!
XANA knows he can’t let Aelita die.
He needs her memory!
Hey, what’s the matter with them?
They're…protecting me.
Aelita’s right.
Use them as allies to defeat the marabounta.
At last! But where’s Ulrich?
Alone with his pride.
Want to tell me what’s going on?
No time. Go straight there.
Odd, Aelita, hang in there.
The cavalry’s coming.
Laser arrow!
Hiyah!
No, Yumi! Not them.
The marabounta’s the one to go after.
Aah!
What is that horrible thing?
One of Jeremie’s bright ideas.
Luckily, XANA’s here to give us a hand.
The world has turned upside down!
(KNOCKING)
Yeah?
Hi.
I came to see how you were.
Yeah, right.
When you have a good chance
to humiliate the competition,
you might as well go for it.
Uh…did I miss something here?
What’s your problem?
You’re my problem.
Uh-uh. No, that’d be too easy, Ulrich.
Let me tell you what’s wrong around here.
My being around Yumi forces you
to ask yourself a question.
A tough question that you can’t answer.
Here’s a piece of friendly advice.
Go and talk to Yumi. From the heart.
Or else, one day, I will.
And then I really will be your problem.
How are you doing, Jeremie?
I’ll never make it.
I’m really the biggest loser ever
to walk the face of the earth.
You couldn’t have known
that my virus would be a problem.
Your virus?
Virus!
What if…
Yeah! Well…
That ought to work!
Hiyah!
Whatever you do, don’t
let it make any headway.
It’ll attack from the rear.
You’re a really good combat general, Odd.
It takes strategy, you know?
The only thing stupider
than a blok is two bloks!
Jeremie, move it!
Things are getting a bit out of hand.
Hey, I’m doing my best, guys.
I think I found a way
to destroy the marabounta!
Odd, I inserted a code for a
deadly virus in one of your arrows
If you hit a sphere with it,
the whole colony will be infected.
But…
No sweat!
Wait!
It’ll only work if you hit the first sphere.
The one I transferred to Lyoko
that created all the others.
It’s at the heart of the marabounta.
Great.
So, how am I supposed to reach
the heart of the marabounta?
On a camel’s back?
(SNARLS)
Odd, it’s the only way.
Charge!
Jeremie, would you mind telling me
how to find the right sphere in all this mess?
I’ll guide you.
Whoa!
Aelita!
Hiyah!
Yumi!
Jeremie!
You’re almost there, Odd.
I’ll give you the exact
location of the first sphere.
It’s okay. I think I found it.
You’ve only got one shot.
Yeah!
Ha ha!
Look!
Don’t buy it, Aelita.
Ulrich’s right.
The marabounta’s gone,
but XANA and his monsters
are still our worst enemy.
He wants your memory at all costs.
Next time you want to play being a mad scientist,
clue us in a little more first, okay?
Well, I really tried to,
but you all had better things to do.
But you’re right, Odd,
because this time I was
a big zero from start to finish.
You found a way out of it,
Jeremie. That’s what counts.
Well, if it isn’t the whole crew.
Well, if it isn’t the brainless frogface.
Ha, ha, ha. You crack me up.
Buy the way, Ulrich,
Are you feeling better after
what happened at the pool.
Cool it, Sissi.
So, what happened at the pool, Ulrich?
Come on! Out with it!
Nothing!
What?
CLOSED CAPTIONING PROVIDED BY
REDDIT.COM/R/CODELYOKO